Jeff Shi

jeff.shi@utexas.edu /jbshi jeffshi.github.io

(214)-235-9679

OPERATIONS RESEARCH ANALYST Captain, USAF

SUMMARY

Operations Research Analyst with 6 years of experience in Data Analytics and Project Management. Experienced in Big Data analytics, R and Python programming, SQL, and providing data-driven insights to senior leadership that influence informed, strategic decision-making. **Separating from military service** and seeking to transition into a corporate Data Science career.

PROGRAMMING & SOFTWARE SKILLS

Proficient: Java, Python, VBA Analytic Tools: Excel, Minitab, Tableau Experienced: R, SQL, Hadoop Software: Office, PyCharm, RStudio

Exposed to: C/C++ OS: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Chief of Assessments (Senior Business Intelligence Analyst) | Tucson, AZ

12th Air Force (Air Forces Southern) | 2014 - Present

- Authors and reports data-driven insights of corporate strategy to the Commander (3-Star General).
- Quantitatively assesses Key Performance Indicators (KPI) of military engagements in South America
- ▶ Wrote R scripts that optimized data analysis during military exercises, saving 20 man-hours.

Chief, Security Trends (Senior Data Analyst) | Camp Arifjan, Kuwait

Combined Joint Task Force – Operation Inherent Resolve (CJTF-OIR) | Nov 2015 – May 2016

- ▶ Drove informed decision-making by regularly briefing executive-level leadership on security trends that affect the campaign to defeat the Islamic State (ISIS).
- ▶ Led data analytics team, providing complex, ad-hoc analysis to support military operations.
- Utilized SQL to query large data sets and gather relevant information to conduct trend analysis.
- ▶ Saved 60-man hours per month by using R and VBA to automate collection, cleaning, and analysis of large structured and unstructured data (>1M data points).

Project Manager, Test Operations | Las Vegas, NV

59th Test and Evaluation Squadron | 2013 - 2014

- ▶ Supervised and mentored analysis team in planning, executing, and analyzing five test programs, fielding \$80 million in new medical evacuation technology and search and rescue tactics.
- Managed land rescue test program to address Africa mission requirements, resulting in the procurement of 60 next-generation vehicles and satisfying Special Operations customer needs.

Senior Operations Research Analyst | Las Vegas, NV

59th Test and Evaluation Squadron | 2012 - 2013

- ▶ Led Test and Evaluation analysis for five acquisitions projects valued at \$60 million.
- Used Excel to analyze and visualize data and drive fielding decisions for experimental products.
- Authored technical reports that informed technical and non-technical stakeholders of test results, enabling data-based acquisition decisions that delivered reliable equipment to warfighters.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology / Class of 2018

MS Student | Computer Science (Machine Learning Focus)

- ▶ Used Python to develop Machine Learning algorithms that performed computational investing.
- Analyzed the performance of 4 randomized optimization algorithms on 2 Kaggle data sets.

New Mexico State University / 2013

MS | Industrial Engineering

University of Texas / 2011

BS | Computer Science